# THAO NGUYEN

W https://thao.ng

E thao\_nguyen@alumni.brown.edu

**P** 650.417.1018

Digital product designer with experience in UI/UX, brand identity, illustration, graphic design, creative coding, and interactive prototyping.

Quick learner who loves impactful, empathetic user-facing work and is interested in social good and helping underserved communities.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **LOCAL PROJECTS · NYC**

Visual Experience Designer | Sept 2021 - Present

Creates visual identities and media experiences, including graphics, presentations, and apps, for clients such as IBM, EY, and National Urban League.

#### **GOOGLE · NYC**

Product Designer | Jan 2019 - July 2021

Owned complete internal brand system, including logo, assets, and animations. Led design workshops and sprints of 8-10 people.

Managed full UX research and design for an internal product, including analytics, user interviews, validation testing, prototyping, and development.

# **TIME INC · NYC**

Web Designer/Developer | Aug 2017 - Jan 2019

Designed components, pages, and sites for InStyle, People, EW, and Essence, such as Fall TV Calendar and Essence Fest 2018 website.

## **SQUARE INC · SF**

UX Engineer | Dec 2016 - June 2017

Managed full UX research and design for an internal product dealing with complex financial data, including, testing, prototyping, and development.

## **EDUCATION**

## **BROWN UNIVERSITY · PROVIDENCE, RI**

BS Applied Math | Sept 2012 - May 2016

Computer Science, Web Apps, UI/UX, Software Engineering, Psychology, HCI

# **SCHOOL OF VISUAL ARTS · NYC**

Continuing Education

Designing Brand Identity, Graphic Design, UX Design, Typography

# **COMMUNITY OUTREACH**

## **LGBT ASYLUM PROJECT · SF**

Visual Designer | Feb 2021 - June 2021

Designed 2021 annual report, containing infographics, illustration spreads, and also refined the organization's visual system and guidelines..

#### SYLVIA RIVERA LAW PROJECT · NYC

UX Designer | Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

Designed workflow and web app for incarcerated LGBTQ immigrants.

#### **DEMOCRATIC SOCIALISTS OF AMERICA · NYC**

Lead UX Designer | Jan 2019 - Present

Designed marketing website, news site, and monthly event calendar.

# **SKILLS**

Adobe CS (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, After Effects) Sketch, Figma, InVision, and other design/prototyping tools React, Javascript, HTML5/CSS3, Java, Python